Contact

jgreenrn@verizon.net

www.linkedin.com/in/john-green-msn-rn-onc-b28a47bb (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Clinical Leadership
Orthopaedic Nursing
Outcomes Management

Languages

English

Certifications

Orthopaedic Nurse Certified (ONC)

John Green MSN, RN, ONC

Nurse Director at Bon Secours Health System Richmond, Virginia Area

Summary

Mission driven professional with a wide range of experience in leadership, direct patient care, team building, and continuous quality improvement. Excellent interpersonal skills and an ability to impact positive change. My top 5 strengths are futuristic, relator, strategic, focus, and discipline.

Experience

Bon Secours Health System 4 years 5 months

Nurse Director March 2019 - Present (1 year 5 months) Richmond, Virginia Area

Clinical Care Leader March 2016 - March 2019 (3 years 1 month) Richmond, Virginia Area

Foster superior clinical outcomes through building key relationships and enhancing a culture of excellence. Promote the use of effective structures and processes, including staff education/development, and manage key clinical process/outcomes metrics at the microsystem level. These include patient safety, quality, and experience of care outcomes.

* Teaching public: pre-operative joint replacement class. This class is designed to prepare patient across the care continuum so they can achieve the best possible outcomes.

Bon Secours Health System 7 years

Charge Nurse

2014 - 2016 (2 years)

 Used data to inform decisions and drive improvement in clinical transformation areas such as length of stay, readmissions, surgical site infections, mortality, CAUTI, and HCAHPS.

- Preceptor for Bon Secours College of Nursing emersion student (404 hours), completed March 29th, 2015, and second student September 2015.
- Process Improvement for Pyxis station. Partnered with pharmacy manager reduce waste in unnecessary stocking of the most expensive medications, preventing nurses from having to draw medication for patients from two Pyxis machines. Completed January 2015.
- Team-building activities such as daily huddles to maintain high team morale and to proactively improve patient safety.
- Tracked and coordinated daily unit level operations, i.e. appropriate staffing, safe patient placement and creating a clean, safe, and healing environment for patients and staff.
- Direct patient care and role model for continuous improvement in communication, service excellence, and positivity in the workplace.
- Mentor/coach staff nurses, PCT for success through shared governance.
- Achievement of RN level 3 through the professional nurse advancement program.

Clinical Coordinator 2012 - 2014 (2 years)

Richmond Virginia

Leadership in the areas of process innovation and improvement, impacting key metrics related to patient safety, quality, and experience of care.

- Developed and implemented a unique process for daily huddles (High Impact Huddles). Engaged staff in recognition of each other, and building a culture of excellence through connecting to the organizations mission and purpose, and driving patient experience and safety.
- Developed and implemented daily Interdisciplinary rounds, which focuses on building relational coordination to impact readmissions, and safe/timely transitions of care.
- Leadership in patient experience (HCAHPS).
- Magnet Site Visit lead for year 2013 and guest speaker at magnet consortium.
- Retroactive and concurrent data abstraction for continuous quality improvement.
- TJC preparation, including chart reviews and other regulatory compliance elements.
- Introduced the concept of "M in the Box" to Bon Secours St. Mary's Hospital after attending a Studer-Group National Conference in Nashville, Tennessee.

October 2013. This is now a BSV wide initiative to improve communication about medications.

- Co-produced and acted in a hospital-wide instruction video for nursing staff development, focusing on a person-centered, and evidence-based approach to bedside shift handoffs.
- Co-produced and acted in a hospital-wide instruction video for staff development, integrating teach-back methodology and "M in the Box" tactic for patient education for new medications (initial improvement on HCAHPS domain communication about meds from first percentile to the 32nd percentile).
- Co-developer of a multimodal pain management program for the spine surgery unit through presentations and consensus at collaborative practice group meetings.

Staff Registered Nurse

2009 - 2012 (3 years)

Coordination and delivery of world-class patient care for diverse patient populations

- Numerous letters and accolades from patients, colleagues, and leaders at St. Mary's Hospital.
- Achievement of RN level 2 through the professional nurse advancement program.
- Member of unit based council, Caritas committee and served as service excellence champion.
- Super user for electronic medical record (connect care).

Education

Liberty University

Master's Degree, Nursing Administration and Leadership (2012 - 2016)

Virginia Commonwealth University

Bachelor's Degree, Kinesiology · (2008 - 2012)

J Sargeant Reynolds Community College

Associate's Degree, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse (2007 - 2009)